Lia Chen Bozarth

lbozarth@umich.edu * www.lbozarth.com * https://github.com/lbozarth * 206-434-2126 * @lia bozarth

OVERVIEW

I'm interested in applying computational methods to study and improve communication quality between heterogeneous actors on social media. I have worked 3 years as a full-stack software developer at top-tier tech firms, followed by 4 years of research experience in the field of computational social science.

Data Analysis Methods: network analysis, natural language processing, machine learning, data scraping and storage, data visualization, statistics, web services, and crowdsourcing (e.g., Mechanical Turk).

Programming Languages and Tools: Python, R, Java, Javascript, PHP & MySQL, Bash, Git, Google Cloud Services, Amazon AWS, Hadoop & Spark, Slurm, ElasticSearch, Mangodb, Pandas, Scikit-learn, Networkx, Twitter streaming API, Reddit API, Stanford NLP libraries, Pycharm and Jupyter.

EDUCATION

Ph.D.	School of Information, University of Michigan	Sep 2016 - Ongoing
B.S.	Computer Science, University of Washington	Sep 2009 - Dec 2012

WORK & RESEARCH HISTORY

University of Michigan

Ph.D. Research Assistant

Sep 2016 - Ongoing

 Adopted computational methods including network analysis, natural language process, and machine learning to examine large-scale social media datasets. Published numerous manuscripts in the field of fake news, online social movements, and political communications studies.

Microsoft Research

Ph.D. Research Intern

May 2018 - Aug 2018

O Built pipeline to continuously fetch Indian politicians' tweets via Twitter API, and then store data in ElasticSearch instances. Supervised the front-end web services and data visualization.

University of Michigan

Graduate Student Instructor

Sep 2017 - Apr 2018

o Collaborated with coursework planning, delivered lectures, and formulated exams.

Google Inc.

Software Developer

Jun 2014 - Feb 2016

• Key engineer in the development and integration of the Revert API in Social Graph

Amazon Inc. Software Developer

Feb 2013 – Jun 2014

• One of the key engineers for the External Payments Batch Processing Service development.

PUBLICATIONS

Peer-reviewed conference and journal articles

- 1. Lia Bozarth, Ceren Budak, "Market Forces: Quantifying the Role of Top Credible Ad Servers in the Fake News Ecosystem", forthcoming, ICWSM (2021)
- 2. Lia Bozarth, Ceren Budak "Toward a Systematic Evaluation Framework of Fake News Classifiers", ICWSM(2020).
- 3. Lia Bozarth, Aparajita Saraf, and Ceren Budak, "How Groundtruth Labeling Impacts Our Understanding of the Spread of Fake News During the 2016 Election", ICWSM(2020).
- 4. Lia Bozarth, Ceren Budak, "Beyond the Eye-Catchers: a Large-Scale Study of Social Movement Organizations' Involvement in Online Protests". New Media & Society (2020)
- 5. Lia Bozarth, Anmol Panda, Joyojeet Pal, "From Greetings to Corruption: Politicians, Political Parties, and Tweeting in India", ICTD (2020).
- 6. Lia Bozarth & Joyojeet Pal, "Twitter Discourse as a Lens into Politicians' Interest in Technology and Development", in proceedings, ICTDX (2018).
- 7. Lia Bozarth & Ceren Budak, "Is Slacktivism Underrated? Measuring the Value of Slacktivists for Online Social Movements", in proceedings, ICWSM (2017).

Non-archival

- 1. Robert Bond, Lia Bozarth, Ceren Budak, Kelly Garrett, Jason Jones, Drew Margolin, "The Case for Studying Obscure Falsehoods", Harvard Kennedy School Misinformation Review (2021)
- 2. Lia Bozarth, Ceren Budak, "Profit for You and Me: Exploring Ad Servers on Fake News Sites", best poster for the *Social Impact* category, MIDAS Symposium (2019)
- 3. Lia Bozarth, Ceren Budak, "A Large-scale Study of Social Movement Organizations (SMOs) in Online Movements", best poster honorable mention, MIDAS TweetCon (2019)
- 4. Joyojeet Pal & Lia Bozarth, "Is Tweeting in Indian Languages Helping Politicians Widen Their Reach?", Economic and Political Weekly (2018).